Phạm Thành Khang

Software Developer



Ha Noi, Viet Nam // (+84) 965 184 529 // khangtpc@gmail.com // Portfolio

PROFILE

Motivated and resourceful Software Developer with more than 3 years of experience, driven by a passion for coding, programming, and creating powerful software solutions. Possessing an in-depth understanding of C#, .NET, VB, Cloud Computing, and SQL, as well as knowledge of emerging technologies, best practices and user experience standards. Aiming to contribute specialized software engineering expertise to a dynamic organization to enable high levels of productivity and customer satisfaction.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Rikkeisoft

Middle Software Developer // 2024-Present

- Collaborate, support and working with cross-region teams (India, London) to develop and implement financial software solutions for Western market client.
- Developed and optimized SQL Server solutions, including designed and maintained complex stored procedures, views, and functions for financial data management.
- Built and maintained SSIS packages cooperate with Control-M job for ETL processes, automating data extraction, transformation, and loading from multiple sources.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to developed C# .NET-based applications, modules and services, enhancing business operations with scalable and efficient solutions.
- Provided CI/CD strategies using GitHub Actions and Azure Pipelines as automating build, test, and deployment workflows.
- Utilized Git and Jira for version control and agile project management, ensuring seamless collaboration and deployment.

FPT SoftWare

Junior Software Developer // 2023-2024

 Small team leader of 5 developer in a project regarding migrating and developing new multi-app WinForms system utilizing C# and .NET Framework with Visual Basic.

- Conducted thorough code reviews for team member.
- Configured and managed Oracle and SQL Server databases.
- Provided and managed data for testing and production environments.
- Established and maintained development and testing environments for the project.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to gather requirements and provide technical guidance.

Junior Software Developer // 2023-2024

- Build out a CI/CD process that triggered with Git commit to automatically builds and deploys Docker images into a Kubernetes cluster.
- Develop a system consists of serverless REST APIs using API Gateway and AWS Lambda, data storage with DynamoDB, AWS S3 and AWS CloudFormation for application resources utilizing.

Fresher Software Developer // 2022 - 2023

 Conduct performance evaluation, logic bug detection, thorough dead code analysis and potential memory leakage risks assessment for a C/C++ based system across Windows and Linux based operating systems.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING

School of Electrical Engineering // Ha Noi University of Science and Technology **2023-2024**

AWS CLOUD DEVELOPER CERTIFICATION

Udacity – FPT Software **2023**

SKILLS + KNOWLEDGE

Language & Framework

C# // Visual Basic // .Net // C/C++ // Typescript // React // Bootstrap // SQL

Databases & ETL

Relational Database (SQL Server, Oracle, ...) // NoSQL (MongoDB) // Query Optimization // Database Design // SSIS // ETL Design Patterns

DevOps

GitHub Actions // Azure DevOps // AWS // Docker // Kubernetes

Other Tools & Soft Skills

Git // Jira // AWS // Problem Solving // Advanced English // Communication

INTERESTS

Music // Traveling // Books // Movies // Food